RG 005:034, Office of the Governor: John Dempsey (1961-1971)
Connecticut State Library
John Dempsey Records
1955-1971
1961-1971
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Governor (1961-1971: Dempsey)
507.75 cubic feet
Gov. Dempsey's correspondence, reading files, subject files, agency files, National Governors' Conference files, New England Governors' Conference files, speeches, official statements, articles, and press releases.
RG005_034
Multiple
Biographical Note
Born: January 3, 1915, Cahir, County Tipperary, Ireland.
College: None.
Political Party: Democrat.
Offices: Mayor of Putnam, Conn., 1947-1961; Lt. Governor of Connecticut, 1959-1961; Governor of Connecticut, 1961-1971.
Died: July 16, 1989, Killingly, Connecticut.
When John Dempsey became Connecticut's governor in 1961 he was the first person to hold this position since the early colonial period who had been born in Europe. Dempsey also began a 30-year period in which the former Puritan colony had only Catholic governors in office. Dempsey was born in Ireland and came to the United States with his family when he was a boy. His father worked in a Putnam textile mill and later Dempsey also worked for a local mill before opening an automobile agency in the community. He married Mary Frey in 1940 and they had four children.
Dempsey held his first local office in Putnam in 1936. In 1947 he was elected mayor and held this position until he became governor in 1961. During these years he also served in the State Legislature (1949-1955), as Governor Ribicoff's executive secretary (1955-1959); and as lieutenant governor (1959-1961). When Ribicoff resigned to become a member of President Kennedy's cabinet, Dempsey was elevated to the position of governor.
On entering the governor's office Dempsey immediately faced a budget deficit that required him to seek an increase in taxes. He was able to have the General Assembly approve funding for more new roads, to expand state institutions, to assist schools, and to provide grants for urban renewal. When the 1962 elections came John Bailey, chairman of the Democratic Party, did not see Dempsey as a strong candidate for reelection, but he always believed that it was best to go with an incumbent for the office. Dempsey won this election with such a large margin that he was in a much more influential position as he began his new term. He also won reelection in 1966. During these years Connecticut was reapportioned into six Congressional Districts, and the State Legislature was reapportioned into 36 districts. When Republican Barry Goldwater was soundly defeated for President in 1964, Connecticut's Republican legislators saw this as a rejection by the public of conservative government. In 1965 and 1967 both parties competed with each other to see which one could develop and fund more state programs. The economy made it possible to do this with little or no new taxation. The courts were improved, new highways were built, the General Fund was created, interest free loans were made available to college students, and the Commission of Higher Education, Department of community Affairs, and the Department of Corrections were all created. Also during these years Connecticut created a new constitution replacing the out-dated one of 1818.
The economy of both Connecticut and the nation began to slow down in 1969 just when many new agencies and programs were being funded. This made it necessary for Dempsey to seek higher taxes, but the General Assembly refused to cooperate with him. A special session was needed to deal with the government's budget problems and it was necessary to increase the sales, cigarette, liquor and corporate taxes. At the same time, with the concurrence of some Democrats, the Assembly created its Legislative Management Committee. This dealt a blow to the influence over legislation that party chairmen such as John Bailey enjoyed.
Dempsey became upset that his own party lacked unity in the General Assembly and that the economy prevented a level of funding that he had enjoyed in the past. He honored a promise that he had made to his family and announced in early 1970 his plan to retire from office in 1971. He had been governor longer than anyone in Connecticut since 1827. One political writer referred to the Dempsey government of the 1960's as a -Decade of Decency. Dempsey enjoyed 18 years of retirement in Putnam and later Killingly. When he died in 1989 he was buried in the cemetery of St. Mary's Church in Putnam. The hospital at the University of Connecticut Medical Center in Farmington is named in his honor, as is the state's Regional Center in Pomfret. The house in Putnam where he grew up and the one he lived in when he became governor still stand. Both are privately owned.
Bibliography
Congressional Quarterly's Guide to United States Elections. Washington, D.C.: Congressional Quarterly, 1994 [CSL call number GIS Ref JK 1967 .C662 1994.
Glashan, Roy R. American Governors and Gubernatorial Elections, 1775-1975. Stillwater, Minn.: Croixside Press, 1975 [CSL call number JK 2447 .G53 1975].
Janick, Herbert F. A Diverse People: Connecticut, 1914 to the Present. Chester, Conn.: Pequot Press, c1975 [CSL call number HistRef Conn Doc St22eacs v. 5].
Lieberman, Joseph. The Legacy, Connecticut Politics, 1930-1980 Hartford, Conn.: Spoonwood Press, 1981 [CSL call number JK 3395 .L53 1981].
Sobel, Robert and John Raimo. Biographical Directory of the Governors of the United States, 1789-1978. Westport, Conn.: Meckler Books, 1978 [CSL call number GIS Ref E 176 .B573].
Van Dusen, Albert E. Connecticut. New York: Random House, 1961 [CSL call number HistRef F 94 .V3].
Scope and Content
Gov. Dempsey's correspondence, reading files, subject files, agency files, National Governors' Conference files, New England Governors' Conference files, speeches, official statements, articles, and press releases.
Arrangement
Series 1. Correspondence, 1961-1971, 206 feet.
Series 2. Reading Files, 1960-1970, 18 feet.
Copies of outgoing letters arranged chronologically.
Series 3. Subject Files, 1960-1971, 89 feet.
Known as special files. Includes some material from earlier governors' files.
Series 4. Agency Files, 1960-1971, 71 feet.
Series 5. Civil Defense Files, 1961-70, 5 feet.
Plans, correspondence, publications, clippings, etc.
Unarranged. No separate container listing.
Series 6. New Haven Rail Road and Connecticut Transportation Authority Files, 1955-1970, 15 feet.
Correspondence, reports, publications, clippings, largely pertaining to the N.H.R.R., its financial difficulties and merger with the Pennsylvania Rail Road, and related matters.
Largely unarranged. No separate container listing.
Series 7. Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations, 1959-1968, 6.5 feet.
Unarranged. No separate container listing.
Series 8. National Governors' Conference, 1958-1970, 8.5 feet.
Unarranged.
Series 9. New England Governors' Conference, 6 feet.
Unarranged.
Series 10. Correspondence Concerning Proposed or Pending Legislation, 1961-1969, 3.5 feet
These are unscientifically selected samples; approximately five times this amount was discarded in 1974. Retained flies pertain to dogs (vivisection), 1961-63; beer and liquor store hours, 1967; optometry, 1963; state aid fore private schools, 1967, and parochial schools, 1969; state budget and taxes, 1969 (including tea bag campaign); miscellaneous 1969 bills by subject.
No separate container listing.
Series 11. Speeches with related materials:
Main files, 1961-1970, 14 feet. Alphabetical by name of group addressed.
Large type copies, 1961-1969, 5 feet. Unarranged.
Background material for speeches, 1961-1970, 1 foot. Alphabetical by subject.
Large type copies, marked for reading, 1961-1970, 10 volumes. Alphabetical by name of group addressed.
Series 12. Official Statements, 1956-1970, 19 feet.
Alphabetical by subject.
Series 13. Articles and Statements by Gov. Dempsey, 1961-1970, 10 inches.
Series 14. Press Releases, 1962-1970, 5 feet.
Chronological.
Series 15. Press Department Files, 1955-1970, 36 feet.
Includes press clippings, releases, documents and a little correspondence. No separate container listings.
Arranged as follows:
1955-1965, by subject
1966-1968, by subject
1969, by subject
1970, by subject
Constitutional Convention, 1965
Articles about Gov. Dempsey
General Assembly material, 1957-1968
Material on teen-age drinking
Photographs (in labeled envelopes) See separate listing.
Campaign material, 1962-1966
Scrapbook of clippings, 1966
Series 16. Highway Safety Files, 1961-1967, 1 foot.
Mostly reference material by subject or title.
No separate container listing.
Series 17. John Dempsey records as Lieutenant Governor, 1958-1960, 1 foot.
Fragmentary and unarranged.
No separate container listing.
Series 18. John Dempsey records as Executive Aide to Gov. Ribicoff and as Mayor of Putnam, 1955-1957, 1 foot.
Mostly alphabetical by correspondent.
No separate container listing.
Series 19. Robert J. Beckwith records, Aide to Gov. Dempsey, 1961-1965, 1 foot.
By subject or correspondent.
No separate container listing.
Series 20. Commission on Equal Employment Opportunity, 2 feet.
No separate container listing.
(See also Subject Files, Box A-253)
Related Material
None.
Index Terms
Persons:
Dempsey, John, 1915-; Beckwith, Robert J.
Subjects:
Dempsey, John, 1915- -- Archives; Connecticut. Office of the Governor -- Archives; Connecticut -- History -- Sources; Connecticut -- Politics and government -- 1951- -- Sources; Governors -- Connecticut -- Archives
Document Types:
Articles; Clippings; Correspondence; Photographs; Press releases; Proclamations; Records; Reports; Speeches
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Series 1. Correspondence, 1961-1971
  - AAA Automobiler - AGVA Foundation, Inc. (Box A-1)
  - Aharonovitz - Allen, Olive (Box A-2)
  - Allen, P. G. - American Enterprise Institute (Box A-3)
  - American Family Life Assurance Company - America's Youth on Parade (Box A-4)
  - Ames - Aphasiac children (Box A-5)
  - Apicella - Aryhli (Box A-6)
  - Asbestos Workers - Automatic Sprinkler Corporation (Box A-7)
  - Automobile accidents - Bailey, John I. (Box A-8)
  - Bailey, John M. - Barbuto (Box A-9)
  - Barcalo - Basilo (Box A-10)
  - Basinas - Beczo (Box A-11)
  - Bedard - Benton, William (Box A-12)
  - Benton, William - Bicycles (Box A-13)
  - Bid - Blalock (Box A-14)
  - Blanc - Boettner (Box A-15)
  - Bogacz - Bousquet (Box A-16)
  - Bouteiller - Bradley, John W. (Box A-17)
  - Bradley, Martina - Brickney (Box A-18)
  - Bride - Brody (Box A-19)
  - Broekhuysen - Brown, Phillips C. (Box A-20)
  - Brown, R. Franklin, Jr. - Bukowy (Box A-21)
  - Bulack - Burritt Mutual Savings Bank (Box A-22)
  - Burroughs - Cady (Box A-23)
  - Caeser - Canevari (Box A-24)
  - Canfield - Carroll, L. Laurence (Box A-25)
  - Carroll, Leo F. - Cathey (Box A-26)
  - Catlin - Cervo (Box A-27)
  - Cesana - Chestnut Hill Road (Box A-28)
  - Chet - Church, Martha K. (Box A-29)
  - Church & State - Clarie (Box A-30)
  - Clark - Coast Guard (Box A-31)
  - Coast Guard - Cole, Gilmoure N. (Box A-32)
  - Cole, Hugh L. M. - Commonweal (Box A-33)
  - Communication Center - Connecticut Audubon Council (Box A-34)
  - Connecticut Bakers Association - Connecticut Publications, Inc. (Box A-35)
  - Connecticut Reformatory - Connolly (Box A-36)
  - Conopast - Cooper (Box A-37)
  - Cooperative Area Manpower Planning System - Coty (Box A-38)
  - Couch - Crazy Horse (Box A-39)
  - Creamer - Cumpton (Box A-40)
  - Cunard Steam-Ship Company - Daley (Box A-41)
  - Dall - Daughter's Education (Box A-42)
  - Daughters of the American Revolution - Dedufour (Box A-43)
  - Dee - de Moura (Box A-44)
  - Dempkowski - DeVinney (Box A-45)
  - DeVit - DiRosa (Box A-46)
  - Disabled American Veterans - Dodd (Box A-47)
  - Dodds - Douskey (Box A-48)
  - Dove - Duester (Box A-49)
  - Dufault - Dwyer (Box A-50)
  - Dyal - Eazor Express, Inc. (Box A-51)
  - Ebner - Eichorn (Box A-52)
  - Eilson - Ems (Box A-53)
  - Encarnacion - Eurto (Box A-54)
  - Evancho - Falkowski (Box A-55)
  - Fallek - Federal Aviation Title Company (Box A-56)
  - Federal Building, Hartford - Fidelity Film Productions (Box A-57)
  - Fiebetham - Fitzgerald, Joseph A. (Box A-58)
  - Fitzgerald Manufacturing Company - Foisey (Box A-59)
  - Folan - Forzley (Box A-60)
  - Fosberg - Frassinelli (Box A-61)
  - Frate - Furlong (Box A-62)
  - Furman - Garcia (Box A-63)
  - Gardella - General Instruments Corporation (Box A-64)
  - General Motors Corporation - Giesen (Box A-65)
  - Gifford - Glibbery (Box A-66)
  - Glick - Goodnow (Box A-67)
  - Goodrich - Graham, Kenneth (Box A-68)
  - Graham, Lawrence - Green (Box A-69)
  - Greenwalt - Gromotike (Box A-70)
  - Gron - Guy (Box A-71)
  - Guydan - Halsted (Box A-72)
  - Halushak - Harpoon Club (Box A-73)
  - Harralson - Hartford Chamber of Commerce (Box A-74)
  - Hartford Capitols - Hasson (Box A-75)
  - Hastedt - Heglund (Box A-76)
  - Hegstrom - Herson (Box A-77)
  - Hertag - Hirtzel (Box A-78)
  - His World- Holdsworth (Box A-79)
  - Holehouse - Horstman (Box A-80)
  - Horticultural Society, Connecticut - Howerton (Box A-81)
  - Howes - Humason (Box A-82)
  - Humbert - Ident (Box A-83)
  - Identification - Independent Western Hat Corporation (Box A-84)
  - India - International Drum Corps Week (Box A-85)
  - International Executive Association - Interstate Commerce Commission (Box A-86)
  - Ioanes - Jackson, N. S. (Box A-87)
  - Jackson, Patrick - Jenning (Box A-88)
  - Jennings - Johnson, Lowell C. (Box A-89)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B. - Jones, Gordon (Box A-90)
  - Jones, H. Wendy - Kaluszka (Box A-91)
  - Kaman - Kear (Box A-92)
  - Kearney - Kemske (Box A-93)
  - Kendall - Kienlen (Box A-94)
  - Kier Photo Service, Inc. - Kivijarv (Box A-95)
  - Kiwanis International - KOMU-TV (Box A-96)
  - Kondas - Kujak (Box A-97)
  - Kula - Lakey (Box A-98)
  - Lalama - Lareau (Box A-99)
  - Largay - Lazzaro (Box A-100)
  - Lea - Lee, Richard C. (Box A-101)
  - Lee, Richard J. - Letts (Box A-102)
  - Leuba - Ligouri (Box A-103)
  - Lihota - Lockett (Box A-104)
  - Lockhart - Lovich (Box A-105)
  - Low and Moderate Income Family Housing - MacCuaig (Box A-106)
  - MacDomnail - Maids, Inc. (Box A-107)
  - Maier - Mansfield Training School (Box A-108)
  - Mansfield, Wendell D. - Markut (Box A-109)
  - Marland - Masons Island Company (Box A-110)
  - Mass Gatherings - Mayott (Box A-111)
  - Mayper - McEwan (Box A-112)
  - McFadden - McKeen (Box A-113)
  - McKegney - Mecum (Box A-114)
  - Medal - Mercy Guild (Box A-115)
  - MERD - Metropolitan Woman's Club (Box A-116)
  - Mets - Miller, Dwight F. (Box A-117)
  - Miller, E. A. - Miss High School of America (Box A-118)
  - Miss Jenny Lind - Monagen (Box A-119)
  - Monahan - Moran, Lillian M. (Box A-120)
  - Moran, Mary - Moscow's Raduga Dancers (Box A-121)
  - Mosel - Muller (Box A-122)
  - Mulligan - Muzzy (Box A-123)
  - My Country Society, Inc. - National Eye Institute (Box A-124)
  - National Fire Protection Association - National Safety Council (Box A-125)
  - National Tax Reform Committee - Nelson, G. A. (Box A-126)
  - Nelson, Gaylord - New England Driver and Traffic Safety Conference (Box A-127)
  - New England Economic Development Region - New Era (Box A-128)
  - New Fairfield Safety Commission - New London YMCA (Box A-129)
  - Newal Building - New Zealand (Box A-130)
  - Ng - Norsworthy (Box A-131)
  - North American Aviation, Inc. - Notuck (Box A-132)
  - Nourie - O'Conor, John F. (Box A-133)
  - O'Day - Omwake (Box A-134)
  - On Job Training Program - Outboard Boating Club of America (Box A-135)
  - Outdoor Advertising Association - Papuga (Box A-136)
  - Paquet - Pathy (Box A-137)
  - Patience - Pelzer (Box A-138)
  - Pember - Personnel Policy Board (Box A-139)
  - Peru - Phillips, Benjamin (Box A-140)
  - Phillips, C. Perrie - Pitman (Box A-141)
  - Plan Resources Corporation - Polzella (Box A-142)
  - Pop Warner Little Scholars, Inc. - Prepall (Box A-143)
  - Preu - Presidential succession (Box A-144)
  - Privacy and Freedom - Przybylo (Box A-145)
  - Psacharopoulos - Pythias, Knights of (Box A-146)
  - Quin - Radziwanowicz (Box A-147)
  - Railway Age - Reardon (Box A-148)
  - Redfern - Regulbuto (Box A-149)
  - Reineke - Reymond Baking Company (Box A-150)
  - Reynolds Aluminum - Ribicoff, Abraham (Box A-151)
  - Ribicoff, Belle - Ripson (Box A-152)
  - Riva - Robins (Box A-153)
  - Robinson School - Rogers Corporation (Box A-154)
  - Rogers, Henry - Rorick (Box A-155)
  - Rosellini - Ruckhaus (Box A-156)
  - Ruda - Ryan (Box A-157)
  - Ryba - St. Justin's Drum Corps (Box A-158)
  - St. King - Samulis (Box A-159)
  - Sandberg - Savoy (Box A-160)
  - Sawchuk - Schlueter (Box A-161)
  - Schobin - Schwolsky (Box A-162)
  - Sciacca - Senior Citizens (Box A-163)
  - Senior Driver - Shatz (Box A-164)
  - Shaughnessy - Sheppard (Box A-165)
  - Sheraton-Chicago Hotel - Sill (Box A-166)
  - Sillari - Sisti (Box A-167)
  - Sitaro - Smith, Fred R. (Box A-168)
  - Smith, Francis L. - Snow (Box A-169)
  - Snowball - Southern New England Telephone Company (Box A-170)
  - Southfield Village - Sprayside Convalescent Hospital (Box A-171)
  - Sprecher - Stanley (Box A-172)
  - Stanley Works - Stausser (Box A-173)
  - Stavely - Stimpson (Box A-174)
  - Stitt - Strong (Box A-175)
  - Stroock - Superior Bakery (Box A-176)
  - Superior Industries Corporation - Szewczyk (Box A-177)
  - Szikla - Tax Foundation (Box A-178)
  - Tax Free Purchases by Senior Citizens - Teluk (Box A-179)
  - Temalis - Thimot (Box A-180)
  - THINK - Timson (Box A-181)
  - Tindall - Torzsa (Box A-182)
  - Toscano - Trezzi (Box A-183)
  - "Trial by Newspaper" - Truck Trailer Trains (Box A-184)
  - Trudeau - Turnbull (Box A-185)
  - Turner - United Automobile Workers (Box A-186)
  - United Builders, Inc. - United States Marshall (Box A-187)
  - [Also contains unarranged Agency Files] (Box A-187)
  - United States National Student Association - Urban League (Box A-189)
  - Urban Mass Transportation - Vartelas (Box A-190)
  - Vedetti - Viagrande (Box A-191)
  - Videlar - Volpe, John (Box A-192)
  - Volpe, Laura - Wallace, Patricia E. (Box A-193)
  - Wallace, Richard A. - Washton (Box A-194)
  - Wasil - Waterschoot (Box A-195)
  - Watertown Town Council - Wedmore (Box A-196)
  - Weiman - West, Frank (Box A-197)
  - West Hartford - Wheeler, Henry P., Jr. (Box A-198)
  - Wheeler, John - Wilcoxson (Box A-199)
  - Wild Areas Act - Wilson, Rev. Grover (Box A-200)
  - Wilson, Haight & Welch - Wiswell (Box A-201)
  - Witalis - Wood (Box A-202)
  - Woodard - Wright, Julia (Box A-203)
  - Wright, Keith G. - Yaple (Box A-204)
  - Yarborough - Yzermans (Box A-205)
  - Z Service Club - Zypko (Box A-206)
- Series 2. Reading Files, 1960-1970
  Copies of outgoing letters.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - 1960 August 1 - 1960 October 27 (Box A-207)
  - 1960 October 28 - 1961 June 10 (Box A-208)
  - 1961 June 12 - 1962 March 23 (Box A-209)
  - 1962 March 26 - 1962 December 11 (Box A-210)
  - 1962 December 12 - 1963 May 31 (Box A-211)
  - 1963 June 1 - 1963 December 13 (Box A-212)
  - 1963 December 16 - 1964 July 7 (Box A-213)
  - 1964 July 8 - 1964 December 31 (Box A-214)
  - 1965 January 4 - 1965 June 23 (Box A-215)
  - 1965 June 24 - 1966 February 17 (Box A-216)
  - 1966 February 18 - 1966 October 18 (Box A-217)
  - 1966 October 19 - 1967 April 7 (Box A-218)
  - 1967 April 10 - 1967 October 25 (Box A-219)
  - 1967 October 26 - 1968 May 14 (Box A-220)
  - 1968 May 15 - 1969 January 14 (Box A-221)
  - 1969 January 15 - 1969 September 16 (Box A-222)
  - 1969 September 17 - 1970 April 6 (Box A-223)
  - 1970 April 6 - 1971 January 5 (Box A-224)
- Series 3. Subject Files, 1960-1971
  Known as "special folders."
  Includes some materials from earlier governors' files.
  - Abortion, 1962, 1967-1970; 2 folders (Box A-225)
  - Accident Prevention Study (United States Public Health Service), 1960-1966 (Box A-225)
  - Accomplishments (Major Legislative under Governor Dempsey's Leadership), 1966 (Box A-225)
  - Accused to Have Counsel - H.B. 2785, P.A. 585, Vetoed, 1959-1963; 2 folders (Box A-225)
  - Achievements of 1961 General Assembly (Box A-225)
  - Administrative Procedure Act S.S.E. 309, P.A. 577, Vetoed, 1961 June 22 (Box A-225)
  - Adult Basic Education, 1966-1969 (Box A-225)
  - Advice and Consent Benefit [July 10,1962, Hartford](re: Conn. Association of Mental Health), 1962 July 10 (Box A-225)
  - Aging, Dept. of - P.A. 814, H.B. 7872, 1909-1971 (Box A-225)
  - Aging, White House Conference on, 1959-1961; 3 folders (Box A-225)
  - Aging, White House Conference on, 1970-1971 (Box A-225)
  - Agriculture, U.S. Dept. of, 1961-1964; 3 folders (Box A-225)
  - Aid to Dependent Children of Unemployed Parents, 1961 (Box A-225)
  - Air Pollution, 1967-1970; 2 folders (Box A-226)
  - Air Quality Control Region, 1969 (Box A-226)
  - Airport Facilities Plan, 1969; half of box (Box A-226)
  - Alabama, Birmingham, 1962-1963 (Box A-226)
  - Alabama, Birmingham and Selma, 1963-1965 (Box A-226)
  - Alcohol Safety Counter-Measures, 1970 (Box A-226)
  - Alcoholism, Commission on, 1958-1968 (Box A-226)
  - Alfano, Charles T., President Pro Tempore of Senate (Copies of appointment letters), 1967-1968 (Box A-227)
  - Allen, Ralph (Trinity College student re: State of Georgia), 1963-1964 (Box A-227)
  - Ambulances, 1963 (Box A-227)
  - American Landmarks Celebration, Action Committee, 1964 (Box A-227)
  - American Life Insurance Association, 1962-1964 (Box A-227)
  - American Revolution Bicentennial Commission, 1969-1970 (Box A-227)
  - Amos Bull House, 1967-1970 (Box A-227)
  - Amusement Tax, 1969-1970 (Box A-227)
  - Andover Lake (Alleged discrimination at), 1963-1964, 1966 (Box A-227)
  - Anemostat Corporation, 1958-1961 (Box A-227)
  - Anonymous, 1967-1970 (Box A-227)
  - Appointments (copies of statements), 1971 (Box A-227)
  - Apollo II (Fifty-state tour), 1970 (Box A-227)
  - Appraisal Fee Schedule, 1964 (Box A-227)
  - Appraisals (Land), 1965-1970 (Box A-227)
  - Area Redevelopment Act, 1962-1963 (Box A-227)
  - Area Redevelopment Coordinating Committee, 1961 (Box A-227)
  - Army Corps Of Engineers, Dept. of (Washington, D.C.), 1961-1968 (Box A-227)
  - Army, U.S. Engineer Division, New England, 1961-1968; 3 folders (Box A-227)
  - Arts, State Commission on, 1965-1969; quarter of box (Box A-227)
  - Arts, State Commission on the, 1962-1968; 2 folders (Box A-228)
  - Aspinook Mill, Jewett City - Files, re: Albert List of List Industries Corp., New York City, efforts to secure client for this building., 1958 (Box A-228)
  - Assessment on Rental Housing for Veterans, S.B. 1002, 1962-1963 (Box A-228)
  - Assigned Risk, 1969; 2 folders (Box A-228)
  - Atomic Energy, 1955-1965; 10 inches (Box A-228)
  - Atomic Energy, 1955-1960; 5 folders, half the box (Box A-229)
  - Atomic Energy Commission, United States, 1956-1960 (Box A-229)
  - Atomic Energy, Governor's Advisory Committee, 1956-1962, 1968; 4 folders (Box A-229)
  - Atomic Energy, Report to the Governor, 1955-1960 (Box A-229)
  - Attendance Reports of State Boards and Commissions, 1964 (Box A-229)
  - Automobile Insurance, 1969 (Box A-229)
  - Avery Point (Transfer of cost Coast Guard property to State of CT), 1968-1969 (Box A-230)
  - Awards (For Government), 1966-1970 (Box A-230)
  - Bail Commissioners, 1969 (Box A-230)
  - Bar Association of Conn., 1955-1968 (Box A-230)
  - Bashan Lake, 1962-1965 (Box A-230)
  - Bazinet, Bertha ("Mom" Bazinet's Welfare and Workshop), 1954-1959 (Box A-230)
  - Beardsley Park (Opposition to proposed Route 25 through the park), 1968 (Box A-230)
  - Beauty Salons, 1963 (Box A-230)
  - Berlin Board of Education (Method of election bill), 1973 (Box A-230)
  - Bethel Connector to Route Interstate 84 (Highway planning report), 1961 (Box A-230)
  - Bethel Police Dept., 1968 (Box A-230)